# Noor Alhijab

Burke, VA | (585) 454-9410 | noor.m.alhijab@gmail.com

Linkedln | Portfolio | GitHub

Software Developer with 3+ years of experience using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, ES6, and Visual Studio in an Agile environment to create innovative solutions and develop software applications. Strong knowledge of IT networking, Microsoft Team Foundation Server and AWS Cloud Practitioner.

#### **SKILLS & Certifications**

Programming: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, ES6 Cloud: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services

Tools: AJAX, API, Visual Studio Code Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals, AWS Cloud

Version Control: Git, GitHub Practitioner

Methodologies: Agile

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### AWS Solutions Architect Associate program/ AWS CloudUp for Her

06/2023 - Present

- Solve business challenges by designing and optimizing cloud solutions using AWS services, the best practices, and the AWS Well-Architected Framework
- Build serverless application on AWS using service like Lambda, SQS, SNS, Kinesis, Aurora, S3, DynamoDB
- Implement cloud compute solutions, storage, databases using variety of AWS services such as EC2, S3, IAM Security Groups, Auto Scaling, ELB, RDS, ECR and VPC

#### Front-end Developer/ Freelance

01/2022 - Present

- Design, develop, and implement web applications using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and SASS to enhance user experiences
  and optimize interface for improved functionality
- Develop fully functional multi-page website using HTML, CSS, and CSS Grid, improving usability access
- · Work in Agile environment to successfully develop web applications

#### Software Developer Apprentice/ Code the Dream

08/2021 -12/2021

- Mastered advanced programming topics focused on JavaScript (functions, loops, arrays, objects, DOM manipulation), HTML, and CSS
- Built foundation to Git, and gained knowledge of debugging and Internet
- Developed skills in AJAX and APT fetch, and built portfolio page using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

#### **PROJECTS**

# Easybank Landing Page Master | Code

- · Created user-friendly website by converting mock-ups to meet user needs and requirements
- Utilized JavaScript to create drop-down menu functionality and Grid for layout

### Insure Landing Page I Code

- Created fully responsive landing page according to designs provided by designer and end-user using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 for mobile navigation toggle
- · Implemented website to provide users with optimal layout depending on device screen size

# Dashboard with Theme Switcher I Code

- Implemented responsive social media dashboard with light and dark theme toggle using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Used CSS Flexbox skills and implemented color theme switcher with JavaScript
- Developed website to allow users to toggle color theme based on preference and view ideal layout

# Template NA News I Code

- · Created multi-age website coded in HTML, CSS, and CSS Grid, honing skills in Grid Layout
- Enhanced user experience and accomplished website objectives by building site structure, navigation, and usability

#### **EDUCATION**

2008 Bachelor of Science (BS), Software Engineering, Baghdad College of Economic Sciences University

2021 The Complete JavaScript Course, Udemy

2021 Modern HTML & CSS from the Beginning, Udemy

2021 Modern HTML & CSS from the Beginning, Udemy

Languages: English, Arabic